Guide to the Rose Goldsen archive of new media art.
Goldsen, Rose archive of new media art
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Rose Goldsen archive of new media art.
8200
Computer media and printed materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art serves as a research repository of new media art and resources.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art serves as a research repository of new media art and resources. The curatorial vision emphasizes digital interfaces and artistic experimentation by international, independent artists. Designed as an experimental center of research and creativity, the Goldsen Archive includes materials by individual artists and collaborates on conceptual experimentation and archival strategies with international curatorial and fellowship projects.
NOTES
All the items in this guide have been cataloged individually and must be requested from their own catalog record. Many are subject to access and use restrictions due to their fragile digital states.
CONTAINER LIST
- Artwork Cataloged Under Collection 8200
  This is the general collection for the Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art. To request an item from this collection please search the catalog for that item.
  - Muntadas: media, architecture, installations, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-136
    Artist: Muntadas
  - Book of shadows, 1996; Archives 8200 CD-137
    Artist: Biggs, Simon
  - Great Wall of China, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-138
  - Moments de Jean-Jacques Rousseau confessions et rêveries, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-139
    Artist: Boissier, Jean-Louis
  - Cyberflesh girlmonster, 1995; Archives 8200 CD-140
  - In my gash, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-141
    Artist: Dement, Linda
  - Shock in the ear, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-142
    Artist: Neumark, Norie
  - Metabody phase 1, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-143
  - Bits of paper books in digital form, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-144
    Artist: Holleley, Douglas
  - Re-reading the book a photographic analysis of Albrecht Dürer's Hieren sind begriffen vier Bücher von menschlicher Proportion, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-145
  - Mauve desert a fiction in translation for CD-ROM, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-146
  - World wide web/million man march, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-147
    Artist: Woolery, Reginald
  - World wide web/million man march, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-148
  - Immemory a CD-ROM, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-150
    Artist: Marker, Chris
  - Marie-Jo Lafontaine installations vidéos, 1979-1999, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-151
    Artist: Lafontaine, Marie-Jo
  - Beyond, 1996; Archives 8200 CD-152
    Artist: Beloff, Zoe
  - Where where there there where, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-153
  - Interactive portfolio, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-154
    Artist: Zellen, Jody
  - Anecdoted archive from the cold war: according to the floor plans of the former Hungarian Worker's Movement (Propoganda) Museum, 1994; Archives 8200 CD-155
    Artist: Legrady, George
  - She loves it, she loves it not women and technology, 1993; Archives 8200 CD-156
    Artist: Tamblyn, Christine
  - Mistaken identities, 1995; Archives 8200 CD-157
  - Borderland, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-158
  - Nazi-loop, 1996; Archives 8200 CD-159
    Artist: Breder, Hans
  - Liquidation photoroman aléatoire, 2001; Archives 8200 CD-160
    Artist: Lefebvre, Michel
  - Am I a natural history museum?, 2001; Archives 8200 CD-161
    Artist: Kelly, Kevin Barry
  - Encoded eye, the archive and its engine house David Tomas, 1998-2000, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-162
  - Fantastic prayers, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-163
  - Divine Comedy digital, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-164
    Artist: Kärkkäinen, Aarre
  - Virtual metropolis, 1996; Archives 8200 CD-165
  - Kiyoshi Furukawa. Masaki Fujihata. Wolfgang Münch small fish, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-166
    Artist: Furukawa, Kiyoshi, Masaki Fujihata, Wolfgang Münch
  - Tamás Waliczky focusing, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-167
    Artist: Waliczky, Tamás
  - Montréal télégraphe le son iconographe, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-168
  - Little movies prolegomena for digital cinema, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-170
    Artist: Manovich, Lev
  - Soft cinema ambient narrative, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-170
  - Poesías animadas de ayer y hoy, 200?; Archives 8200 CD-171
    Artist: Ardévol, Alvaro
  - Web DQ Don Quijote en Barcelona, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-172
    Artist: Casanova, Cristina
  - Virtualidade sabia (Sabiá virtuality), 2003; Archives 8200 CD-173
    Artist: Pinto, Regina Célia
  - Bibliotheca das maravilhas (Library of marvels), 2003; Archives 8200 CD-174
  - Espoo-Alexanderplatz, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-175
  - Ocular convergence, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-176
    Artist: Goldfarb, Brian
  - Electric leak the north of it, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-177
    Artist: Office for Contemporary Art Norway
  - Esoth eric off-line/on-line project, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-178
    Artist: Man, Calin
  - Advent, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-179
    Artist: Gillman, Clive
  - Home project, 2004; Archives 8200 CD-180
    Artist: Barbier, Annette
  - As de bastos, tijeras en cruz, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-181
    Artist: Alvarez, Julián
  - Mixed greens a do-it-yourself-movie about identity, belonging, and what we desire, 2004; Archives 8200 CD-182
    Artist: Citron, Michelle
  - Web XXX manual of leisure and licentiousness, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-184
  - Cocktails & appetizers, 2001; Archives 8200 CD-185
  - As American as apple pie food, sex, family, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-186
  - Vamos a contar mentiras (Let's tell lies), 1999; Archives 8200 CD-187
    Artist: Casanova, Cristina.
  - Night in the chapel, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-188
    Artist: FMOL Trio.
  - Live at Metrònom, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-189
  - Köln concert, 2001; Archives 8200 CD-190
  - Lago mar algo barco chuva uma experiência em net.poesia, 2001; Archives 8200 CD-191
    Artist: Antonio, Jorge Luiz.
  - Beyond Manzanar, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-192
    Artist: Thiel, Tamiko.
  - Life after wartime, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-193
    Artist: Gibson, Ross
  - Solo cauce, 2004; Archives 8200 CD-194
    Artist: Baranda, María.
  - Courier a digital video, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-195
    Artist: Tashiro, C. S. (Charles Shiro)
  - Little movies, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-196
  - Work of art, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-197
  - Donald Rodney autoicon v1.0, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-198
    Artist: Rodney, Donald, 1961-1998.
  - Chinese whisper 3 an interactive performance at studio Eickholt, New York, August 28, 2002, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-199
    Artist: Lanfermeijer, Ruud.
  - No accommodation the remix, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-200
    Artist: DJ Spooky That Subliminal Kid.
  - LTK live, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-201
    Artist: LTK Commune (Musical group)
  - Waiting for Julius a digital video, 2001; Archives 8200 CD-202
  - Caprice a digital video, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-203
  - Babylon Ministry of Misinformation, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-205
    Artist: And, Miekal.
  - Realpolitik project, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-206
    Artist: Calovski, Yane.
  - Eleven angles, 2004; Archives 8200 CD-207
    Artist: Colorform (Musician).
  - Groupe Molior, 200u; Archives 8200 CD-208
    Artist: Groupe Molior (Group of artists)
  - Quack-project, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-211
    Artist: Dr. Quack.
  - Rosalind Brodsky and the satellites of Lvov, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-212
    Artist: Treister, Suzanne
  - RK, 2005; Archives 8200 CD-213
    Artist: Kramer, Roger (Artist)
  - World Wide catalogue, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-214
  - Sound art: beyond music, between categories, 2007; Archives 8200 CD-2149
    Artist: Licht, Alan.
  - Culture vs. the Martians, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-239
  - #FFFFFF, 2001; Archives 8200 CD-240
    Artist: Jones, Art.
  - Archival quality, 1998; Archives 8200 CD-241
    Artist: Tamblyn, Christine.
  - Human body an invisible ecosystem, 1996; Archives 8200 CD-242
    Artist: Tacha, Athena
  - Mouchette, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-243
  - Raw music material: electronic music DJs today, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-254
  - No other symptoms: time traveling with Rosalind Brodsky, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-255
  - Fig trees, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-256
    Artist: Greyson, John
  - Retina burn, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-257
    Artist: Polli, Andrea.
  - Calling to mind, 2005; Archives 8200 CD-258
    Artist: Thorington, Helen.
  - Aural cultures, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-259
  - Karā azu a konseputo: dejitaru jidai no shikisairon, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-260
  - Family in Brussels, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-261
    Artist: Akerman, Chantal.
  - Site specific sound, 2004; Archives 8200 CD-262
    Artist: LaBelle, Brandon.
  - Sonic process: une nouvelle géographie des sons, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-263
  - Over/time, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-264
    Artist: Bertolo, Diane.
  - Atmospherics/weather works, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-265
  - Nouveau Western, a.k.a. Alula Price, 2005; Archives 8200 CD-266
    Artist: Halpern, Tal.
  - Fleeting traces in blank spaces: animation series, 2007; Archives 8200 CD-267
    Artist: Nudelman, Mike.
  - Fleeting traces in blank spaces: longer version, 2007; Archives 8200 CD-268
  - Improvisation technologies a tool for the analytical dance eye, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-269
  - Postcard from Tunis v[ersion] 2.0., Undated; Archives 8200 CD-270
    Artist: Pryor, Sally.
  - Xchange, 1992; Archives 8200 CD-271
  - Secret hotel: Janet Cardiff + George Bures Miller, 2005; Archives 8200 CD-275
  - Exposition sauvage, 1999; Archives 8200 CD-337
    Artist: Cahen, Xavier.
  - Déjouer l'image: créations électroniques et numériques, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-338
    Artist: Duguet, Anne-Marie
  - Interagir avec les technologies numériques, 2004; Archives 8200 CD-339
  - Vida 9.0 Arte y Vida Artificial, convocatoria 2006 = 2006 call for participation, 2006; Archives 8200 CD-340
    Artist: Concurso Internacional de Arte y Vida Artificial (2006)
  - Just from Cynthia, 1996; Archives 8200 CD-341
    Artist: Sorbelli, Alberto.
  - Christof Migone--sound voice perform, 2005; Archives 8200 CD-343
    Artist: Migone, Christof.
  - Actualité du virtuel actualizing the virtual, 1997; Archives 8200 CD-344
  - Body and the object: Ann Hamilton, 1984-1996, 1996; Archives 8200 CD-345
    Artist: Hamilton, Ann
  - Women in electronic music, 1977 new music for electronic and recorded media, 2006; Archives 8200 CD-481
  - 7e Biennale d'art contemporain de Lyon: 18 septembre 2003-4 janvier 2004, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-556
    Artist: Biennale d'art contemporain (Lyon, France) (7th: 2003)
  - Prix Ars Electronica 92, 1992; Archives 8200 CD-2033
  - CyberArts 2002 digital musics, 2002; Archives 8200 CD-2034
  - Cyber arts 2000 Prix ars electronica: digital musics, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-2035
  - Key, 1995; Archives 8200 CD-2036
    Artist: Monk, Meredith.
  - Prix 89, 1989; Archives 8200 CD-2037
    Artist: Ars Electronica.
  - Anthology of noise & electronic music, 2007; Archives 8200 CD-2038
  - Anthology of noise & electronic music, 2005; Archives 8200 CD-2039
  - Literature nation + many others, Undated; Archives 8200 CD-204
  - Anthology of noise & electronic music, 2004; Archives 8200 CD-2040
  - Judd, 2007; Archives 8200 CD-2410
    Artist: Vitiello, Stephen.
  - Composers Inside Electronics, 2007; Archives 8200 CD-2411
    Artist: Composers Inside Electronics.
  - INFOS '00: seminar INFOS '00: net.art, 2000; Archives 8200 CD-3244-3245
    Artist: INFOS (2000: Ljubljana)
  - Ghost city, 2003; Archives 8200 CD-3246
  - Sally, or, The bubble burst, 2003; Archives 8200 DVD-100
    Artist: Dove, Toni
  - No cum shot, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-101
    Artist: Scher, Julia.
  - Humans, 2009; Archives 8200 DVD-1012
    Artist: Daniels, David
  - By design ambient works by three of the world's legendary creatives set to music, 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-1013
  - No, I never lipsync'd, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-102
  - Carrizo quartet seismic memory along the San Andreas fault, 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-103
    Artist: McPhee, Christina.
  - Advanced beauty, 2009; Archives 8200 DVD-1035
  - Coco Fusco I like girls in uniform, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-1036
  - Onedotzero_select DVD⁵ adventures in moving image, 2007; Archives 8200 DVD-1037
  - Onedotzero select DVD⁴ [short films], 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-1038
  - Beautiful world, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-1039
  - Carrizo-Parkfield diaries a project, 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-104
  - Willie Doherty, 2009; Archives 8200 DVD-1040
  - Claire Barclay, openwide: exhibition 7 February-12 April 2009, 2009; Archives 8200 DVD-1041
  - CyberArts 2006 international compendium Prix Ars Electronica 2006, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-1042
  - Vida 9.0 Arte y Vida Artificial, 2007; Archives 8200 DVD-1043
  - Sub_scapeProof a machinima, 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-105
    Artist: Waterson, Sarah.
  - Bystander documentation April 2006, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-106
    Artist: Richards, Kate.
  - River of many sides excerpts from the performance, Chicago 2004, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-108
    Artist: Barbier, Annette.
  - Annette Barbier, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-109
  - When it hit me multimedia design graduand exhibition, 2004, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-110
    Artist: Monash University. Faculty of Art & Design.
  - Bits of memory, 200u; Archives 8200 DVD-112
    Artist: Quintanilla, Grace.
  - Nací mujer = Born a woman whatever that means, 2003; Archives 8200 DVD-113
  - Guantanamo! liberty and justice for all, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-114
  - Guantanamo now! liberty and justice for all: work-in-progress, Spring, 2005, Cornell University, 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-114a
  - One day in 1999 an epic of ordinary life, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-115
  - Etc., etc., etc. a digital video, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-116
  - 4X selected digital short subjects, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-117
  - Day of the act, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-118
  - Naked bastard, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-119
  - Around and about: a performative view, 2000; Archives 8200 DVD-1194
  - Somewhere, everywhere, nowhere, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-1451
  - Reline a video artist DVD compilation, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-152
  - Latent figure protocol, 2007; Archives 8200 DVD-153
    Artist: Vanouse, Paul.
  - PED. Chongqing, 2006, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-154
  - Exchange program, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-155
    Artist: Mandiberg, Michael.
  - Queensbridge wind power, 200u; Archives 8200 DVD-156
  - Memoires of a cyborg complete video set, selected images, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-157
  - Reynald Drouhin: frags, 2003; Archives 8200 DVD-158
  - Noise driven ambient audio and visuals, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-159
  - DC 9/11: the evildoers' remix, 200u; Archives 8200 DVD-160
    Artist: MTAA (Group of artists)
  - Calling to mind, 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-161
  - Lovemad, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-162
    Artist: Onomé, Ekeh.
  - Title TK: notes, 1974-1992, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-163
    Artist: Kuntzel, Thierry
  - Amplitude of chance: the horizon of occurrences, 2001; Archives 8200 DVD-164
    Artist: Sato, Minoru
  - (Dis) locations, 2001; Archives 8200 DVD-165
  - Conceiving Ada, 1999; Archives 8200 DVD-166
  - Tenderly yours, 2005; Archives 8200 DVD-167
    Artist: Horvath, Peter J.
  - Postcard from Tunis, 1997; Archives 8200 DVD-168
  - Notes towards the complete works of Shakespeare, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-185
  - Coded characters: media art, 2003; Archives 8200 DVD-187
    Artist: Scott, Jill
  - Seeing/hearing/speaking, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-1961-1962
    Artist: Iimura, Takahiko
  - Aspect the chronicle of new media art, 2003; Archives 8200 DVD-574-575, 581-584, 760-762
  - Caterina Davinio, 2007; Archives 8200 DVD-585
    Artist: Davinio, Caterina.
  - Deke Weaver, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-586
    Artist: Weaver, Deke.
  - Vida 8.0 arte y vida artificial, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-587
    Artist: ARCO (Art fair) (2006: Madrid, Spain)
  - Mouvement des images, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-588
  - From a classical position, 2007; Archives 8200 DVD-589
    Artist: Forsythe, William.
  - I do not know what it is I am like, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-590
  - Macht des Wortes = I can't tell you: Xenon for Duisburg, 2006; Rare Books 8200 DVD-737
    Artist: Holzer, Jenny
  - Kinema ikon worx, 2005; Rare Books 8200 DVD-744
  - Ag4 media facades, 2006; Archives 8200 DVD-745
  - Animated painting, 2007; Archives 8200 DVD-746
  - Conchita N=amour, 2007; Rare Books 8200 DVD-747
  - Eizō sakka hyakunin = Japanese motion graphic creators 2007, 2007; Rare Books 8200 DVD-748
  - Computerfinearts collection, 1997-2007, 2007; Archives 8200 DVD-749
  - Journal of film and video, 1984; Rare Books 8200 DVD-750
  - Igloo, 4 projects documentation DVD with sound, 2006; Rare Books 8200 DVD-751
  - Rubicon, 2004; Rare Books 8200 DVD-752
  - Reline, 2006; Rare Books 8200 DVD-753
  - SubRosa selected projects, 2000-2005: six performances and video works, 2005; Rare Books 8200 DVD-754
  - Tammy Renée Brackett new work, 2005; Rare Books 8200 DVD-755
  - Disturbance excerpts, 2006; Rare Books 8200 DVD-756
    Artist: Paris, Bob
  - Passing:, 2006; Rare Books 8200 DVD-757
  - Hatsu Yume First dream, 2006; Rare Books 8200 DVD-758
  - Formula, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-98
    Artist: Ikeda, Ryoji
  - Mirrors & smoke an interactive performance in virtual place, 2001; Archives 8200 DVD-985
    Artist: Jones, Philip Mallory.
  - Complete artintact komplett CD-ROMagazin interaktiver Kunst, vols. 1-5, 1994-1999, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-986
  - David Rokeby, 2004; Archives 8200 DVD-987
    Artist: Rokeby, David
  - Digital snow, 2002; Archives 8200 DVD-99
    Artist: Snow, Michael
  - Clearing, 1994; Archives 8200 FD1-2
  - Judith Barry installations, 1998; Archives 8200 V-879
    Artist: Barry, Judith
  - Vida 5.0, 2002; Archives 8200 V-880
    Artist: Concurso Internacional de Arte y Vida Artificial (2002: Madrid, Spain)
  - Evolving traditions: artists working in new media, 2002; Archives 8200 V-9368
    Artists: Mark Amerika, Tennessee Rice Dixon, Toni Dove, Troika Ranch